
<xml>
<poem>
<author>
                            Emily Dickinson
</author>
<title>
                    Wild nights - Wild nights! (269)
</title>
<text>
                    Wild nights - Wild nights!&lt;br&gt;
 Were I with thee&lt;br&gt;
 Wild nights should be&lt;br&gt;
 Our luxury!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 Futile - the winds -&lt;br&gt;
 To a Heart in port -&lt;br&gt;
 Done with the Compass -&lt;br&gt;
 Done with the Chart!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 Rowing in Eden -&lt;br&gt;
 Ah - the Sea!&lt;br&gt;
 Might I but moor - tonight -&lt;br&gt;
 In thee!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

</text>
</poem>
<poem>
<author>
                            Emily Dickinson
</author>
<title>
                    My Life had stood - a Loaded Gun (764)
</title>
<text>
                    My Life had stood - a Loaded Gun -&lt;br&gt;
 In Corners - till a Day&lt;br&gt;
 The Owner passed - identified -&lt;br&gt;
 And carried Me away -&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 And now We roam in Sovreign Woods -&lt;br&gt;
 And now We hunt the Doe -&lt;br&gt;
 And every time I speak for Him&lt;br&gt;
 The Mountains straight reply -&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 And do I smile, such cordial light&lt;br&gt;
 Opon the Valley glow -&lt;br&gt;
 It is as a Vesuvian face&lt;br&gt;
 Had let it’s pleasure through -&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 And when at Night - Our good Day done -&lt;br&gt;
 I guard My Master’s Head -&lt;br&gt;
 ’Tis better than the Eider Duck’s&lt;br&gt;
 Deep Pillow - to have shared -&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 To foe of His - I’m deadly foe -&lt;br&gt;
 None stir the second time -&lt;br&gt;
 On whom I lay a Yellow Eye -&lt;br&gt;
 Or an emphatic Thumb -&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 Though I than He - may longer live&lt;br&gt;
 He longer must - than I -&lt;br&gt;
 For I have but the power to kill,&lt;br&gt;
 Without - the power to die -&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

</text>
</poem>
<poem>
<author>
                            Wallace Stevens
</author>
<title>
                    Anecdote of the Jar
</title>
<text>
                    I placed a jar in Tennessee,&lt;br&gt;
 And round it was, upon a hill.&lt;br&gt;
 It made the slovenly wilderness&lt;br&gt;
 Surround that hill.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 The wilderness rose up to it,&lt;br&gt;
 And sprawled around, no longer wild.&lt;br&gt;
 The jar was round upon the ground&lt;br&gt;
 And tall and of a port in air.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 It took dominion everywhere.&lt;br&gt;
 The jar was gray and bare.&lt;br&gt;
 It did not give of bird or bush,&lt;br&gt;
 Like nothing else in Tennessee.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

</text>
</poem>
<poem>
<author>
                            Wallace Stevens
</author>
<title>
                    Anecdote of the Prince of Peacocks
</title>
<text>
                    In the moonlight&lt;br&gt;
 I met Berserk,&lt;br&gt;
 In the moonlight&lt;br&gt;
 On the bushy plain.&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
 Oh, sharp he was&lt;br&gt;
 As the sleepless!&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
 And, “Why are you red&lt;br&gt;
 In this milky blue?”&lt;br&gt;
 I said.&lt;br&gt;
 “Why sun-colored,&lt;br&gt;
 As if awake&lt;br&gt;
 In the midst of sleep?”&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
 “You that wander,”&lt;br&gt;
 So he said,&lt;br&gt;
 “On the bushy plain,&lt;br&gt;
 Forget so soon.&lt;br&gt;
 But I set my traps&lt;br&gt;
 In the midst of dreams.”&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
 I knew from this&lt;br&gt;
 That the blue ground&lt;br&gt;
 Was full of blocks&lt;br&gt;
 And blocking steel.&lt;br&gt;
 I knew the dread&lt;br&gt;
 Of the bushy plain,&lt;br&gt;
 And the beauty&lt;br&gt;
 Of the moonlight&lt;br&gt;
 Falling there,&lt;br&gt;
 Falling&lt;br&gt;
 As sleep falls&lt;br&gt;
 In the innocent air.&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

</text>
</poem>
<poem>
<author>
                            Wallace Stevens
</author>
<title>
                    Bantams in Pine-Woods
</title>
<text>
                    Chieftain Iffucan of Azcan in caftan&lt;br&gt;
 Of tan with henna hackles, halt!&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
 Damned universal cock, as if the sun&lt;br&gt;
 Was blackamoor to bear your blazing tail.&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
 Fat! Fat! Fat! Fat! I am the personal.&lt;br&gt;
 Your world is you. I am my world.&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
 You ten-foot poet among inchlings. Fat!&lt;br&gt;
 Begone! An inchling bristles in these pines,&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
 Bristles, and points their Appalachian tangs,&lt;br&gt;
 And fears not portly Azcan nor his hoos.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

</text>
</poem>
<poem>
<author>
                            John Ashbery
</author>
<title>
                    Farm Implements and Rutabagas in a Landscape
</title>
<text>
                    The first of the undecoded messages read: “Popeye sits in thunder,&lt;br&gt;
 Unthought of. From that shoebox of an apartment,&lt;br&gt;
 From livid curtain’s hue, a tangram emerges: a country.”&lt;br&gt;
 Meanwhile the Sea Hag was relaxing on a green couch: “How pleasant&lt;br&gt;
 To spend one’s vacation &lt;em&gt;en la casa de Popeye,&lt;/em&gt;” she scratched&lt;br&gt;
 Her cleft chin’s solitary hair. She remembered spinach&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 And was going to ask Wimpy if he had bought any spinach.&lt;br&gt;
 “M’love,” he intercepted, “the plains are decked out in thunder&lt;br&gt;
 Today, and it shall be as you wish.” He scratched&lt;br&gt;
 The part of his head under his hat. The apartment&lt;br&gt;
 Seemed to grow smaller. “But what if no pleasant&lt;br&gt;
 Inspiration plunge us now to the stars? &lt;em&gt;For this is my country.&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 Suddenly they remembered how it was cheaper in the country.&lt;br&gt;
 Wimpy was thoughtfully cutting open a number 2 can of spinach&lt;br&gt;
 When the door opened and Swee’pea crept in. “How pleasant!”&lt;br&gt;
 But Swee’pea looked morose. A note was pinned to his bib. “Thunder&lt;br&gt;
 And tears are unavailing,” it read. “Henceforth shall Popeye’s apartment&lt;br&gt;
 Be but remembered space, toxic or salubrious, whole or scratched.”&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 Olive came hurtling through the window; its geraniums scratched&lt;br&gt;
 Her long thigh. “I have news!” she gasped. “Popeye, forced as you know to flee the country&lt;br&gt;
 One musty gusty evening, by the schemes of his wizened, duplicate father, jealous of the apartment&lt;br&gt;
 And all that it contains, myself and spinach&lt;br&gt;
 In particular, heaves bolts of loving thunder&lt;br&gt;
 At his own astonished becoming, rupturing the pleasant&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 Arpeggio of our years. No more shall pleasant&lt;br&gt;
 Rays of the sun refresh your sense of growing old, nor the scratched&lt;br&gt;
 Tree-trunks and mossy foliage, only immaculate darkness and thunder.”&lt;br&gt;
 She grabbed Swee’pea. “I’m taking the brat to the country.”&lt;br&gt;
 “But you can’t do that—he hasn’t even finished his spinach,”&lt;br&gt;
 Urged the Sea Hag, looking fearfully around at the apartment.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 But Olive was already out of earshot. Now the apartment&lt;br&gt;
 Succumbed to a strange new hush. “Actually it’s quite pleasant&lt;br&gt;
 Here,” thought the Sea Hag. “If this is all we need fear from spinach&lt;br&gt;
 Then I don’t mind so much. Perhaps we could invite Alice the Goon over”—she scratched&lt;br&gt;
 One dug pensively—“but Wimpy is such a country&lt;br&gt;
 Bumpkin, always burping like that.” Minute at first, the thunder&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 Soon filled the apartment. It was domestic thunder,&lt;br&gt;
 The color of spinach. Popeye chuckled and scratched&lt;br&gt;
 His balls: it sure was pleasant to spend a day in the country.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

</text>
</poem>
<poem>
<author>
                            Emily Dickinson
</author>
<title>
                    I felt a Funeral, in my Brain, (340)
</title>
<text>
                    I felt a Funeral, in my Brain,&lt;br&gt;
 And Mourners to and fro&lt;br&gt;
 Kept treading - treading - till it seemed&lt;br&gt;
 That Sense was breaking through -&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 And when they all were seated,&lt;br&gt;
 A Service, like a Drum -&lt;br&gt;
 Kept beating - beating - till I thought&lt;br&gt;
 My mind was going numb -&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 And then I heard them lift a Box&lt;br&gt;
 And creak across my Soul&lt;br&gt;
 With those same Boots of Lead, again,&lt;br&gt;
 Then Space - began to toll,&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 As all the Heavens were a Bell,&lt;br&gt;
 And Being, but an Ear,&lt;br&gt;
 And I, and Silence, some strange Race,&lt;br&gt;
 Wrecked, solitary, here -&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 And then a Plank in Reason, broke,&lt;br&gt;
 And I dropped down, and down -&lt;br&gt;
 And hit a World, at every plunge,&lt;br&gt;
 And Finished knowing - then -&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

</text>
</poem>
<poem>
<author>
                            Emily Dickinson
</author>
<title>
                    There is no Frigate like a Book (1286)
</title>
<text>
                    There is no Frigate like a Book&lt;br&gt;
 To take us Lands away&lt;br&gt;
 Nor any Coursers like a Page&lt;br&gt;
 Of prancing Poetry –&lt;br&gt;
 This Traverse may the poorest take&lt;br&gt;
 Without oppress of Toll –&lt;br&gt;
 How frugal is the Chariot&lt;br&gt;
 That bears the Human Soul –&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

</text>
</poem>
<poem>
<author>
                            John Ashbery
</author>
<title>
                    Like a Sentence
</title>
<text>
                    How little we know,&lt;br&gt;
 and when we know it!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 It was prettily said that “No man&lt;br&gt;
 hath an abundance of cows on the plain, nor shards&lt;br&gt;
 in his cupboard.” Wait! I think I know who said that! It was . . .&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 Never mind, dears, the afternoon&lt;br&gt;
 will fold you up, along with preoccupations&lt;br&gt;
 that now seem so important, until only a child&lt;br&gt;
 running around on a unicycle occupies center stage.&lt;br&gt;
 Then what will you make of walls? And I fear you&lt;br&gt;
 will have to come up with something,&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 be it a terraced gambit above the sea&lt;br&gt;
 or gossip overheard in the marketplace.&lt;br&gt;
 For you see, it becomes you to be chastened:&lt;br&gt;
 for the old to envy the young,&lt;br&gt;
 and for youth to fear not getting older,&lt;br&gt;
 where the paths through the elms, the carnivals, begin.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 And it was said of Gyges that his ring&lt;br&gt;
 attracted those who saw him not,&lt;br&gt;
 just as those who wandered through him were aware&lt;br&gt;
 only of a certain stillness, such as precedes an earache,&lt;br&gt;
 while lumberjacks in headbands came down to see what all the fuss was about,&lt;br&gt;
 whether it was something they could be part of&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;sans&lt;/em&gt; affront to self-esteem.&lt;br&gt;
 And those temple hyenas who had seen enough,&lt;br&gt;
 nostrils aflare, fur backing up in the breeze,&lt;br&gt;
 were no place you could count on,&lt;br&gt;
 having taken a proverbial powder&lt;br&gt;
 as rifle butts received another notch.&lt;br&gt;
 I, meanwhile . . . I was going to say I had squandered spring&lt;br&gt;
 when summer came along and took it from me&lt;br&gt;
 like a terrier a lady has asked one to hold for a moment&lt;br&gt;
 while she adjusts her stocking in the mirror of a weighing machine.&lt;br&gt;
 But here it is winter, and wrong&lt;br&gt;
 to speak of other seasons as though they exist.&lt;br&gt;
 Time has only an agenda&lt;br&gt;
 in the wallet at his back, while we&lt;br&gt;
 who think we know where we are going unfazed&lt;br&gt;
 end up in brilliant woods, nourished more than we can know&lt;br&gt;
 by the unexpectedness of ice and stars&lt;br&gt;
 and crackling tears. We’ll just have to make a go of it,&lt;br&gt;
 a run for it. And should the smell of baking cookies appease&lt;br&gt;
 one or the other of the olfactory senses, climb down&lt;br&gt;
 into this wagonload of prisoners.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 The meter will be screamingly clear then,&lt;br&gt;
 the rhythms unbounced, for though we came&lt;br&gt;
 to life as to a school, we must leave it without graduating&lt;br&gt;
 even as an ominous wind puffs out the sails&lt;br&gt;
 of proud feluccas who don’t know where they’re headed,&lt;br&gt;
 only that a motion is etched there, shaking to be free.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

</text>
</poem>
<poem>
<author>
                            John Ashbery
</author>
<title>
                    The Short Answer
</title>
<text>
                    I am forced to sleepwalk much of the time.&lt;br&gt;
 We hold on to these old ways, are troubled&lt;br&gt;
 sometimes and then the geyser goes away,&lt;br&gt;
 time gutted. In and of itself there is&lt;br&gt;
 no great roar, force pitted against force that&lt;br&gt;
 makes up in time what it loses in speed.&lt;br&gt;
 The waterfalls, the canyon, a royal I-told-you-so&lt;br&gt;
 comes back to greet us at the beginning.&lt;br&gt;
 How was your trip? Oh I didn’t last&lt;br&gt;
 you see, folded over like the margin&lt;br&gt;
 of a dream of the thing-in-itself. Well, and&lt;br&gt;
 what have we come to? A paper-thin past,&lt;br&gt;
 just so, and ‘tis pity. We regurgitate&lt;br&gt;
 old anthems and what has come to pass, and why&lt;br&gt;
 dwell on these. Why make things more difficult&lt;br&gt;
 than they already are? Because if it’s boring&lt;br&gt;
 in a different way, that’ll be interesting too.&lt;br&gt;
 That’s what I say.&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
 That rascal, he jumped over the fence.&lt;br&gt;
 I’m wiping my pince-nez now. Did you ever hear from&lt;br&gt;
 the one who said he’d be back once it was over,&lt;br&gt;
 who eluded me even in my sleep? That was a particularly&lt;br&gt;
 promising time, we thought. Now the sun’s out&lt;br&gt;
 and it’s raining again. Just like a day from&lt;br&gt;
 the compendium. I’ll vouch for you,&lt;br&gt;
 and we can go on scrolling as though nothing had risen,&lt;br&gt;
 the horizon forest looks back at us. The preacher&lt;br&gt;
 shook his head, the evangelist balanced two spools&lt;br&gt;
 at the end of his little makeshift rope. We’d gone too far.&lt;br&gt;
 We’d have to come back in a day or so.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

</text>
</poem>
</xml>
