
<xml>
<poem>
<author>
Wallace Stevens
</author>
<title>
Nomad Exquisite
</title>
<text>
As the immense dew of Florida&lt;br&gt;
Brings forth&lt;br&gt;
The big-finned palm&lt;br&gt;
And green vine angering for life,&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
As the immense dew of Florida&lt;br&gt;
Brings forth hymn and hymn&lt;br&gt;
From the beholder,&lt;br&gt;
Beholding all these green sides&lt;br&gt;
And gold sides of green sides,&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
And blessed mornings,&lt;br&gt;
Meet for the eye of the young alligator,&lt;br&gt;
And lightning colors&lt;br&gt;
So, in me, come flinging&lt;br&gt;
Forms, flames, and the flakes of flames.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

</text>
</poem>
<poem>
<author>
Wallace Stevens
</author>
<title>
The House Was Quiet and The World Was Calm
</title>
<text>
The house was quiet and the world was calm.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size: 1em;"&gt;The reader became the book; and summer night&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size: 1em;"&gt;Was like the conscious being of the book.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size: 1em;"&gt;The house was quiet and the world was calm.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size: 1em;"&gt;The words were spoken as if there was no book,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size: 1em;"&gt;Except that the reader leaned above the page,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size: 1em;"&gt;Wanted to lean, wanted much most to be&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size: 1em;"&gt;The scholar to whom his book is true, to whom&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size: 1em;"&gt;The summer night is like a perfection of thought.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size: 1em;"&gt;The house was quiet because it had to be.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size: 1em;"&gt;The quiet was part of the meaning, part of the mind:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size: 1em;"&gt;The access of perfection to the page.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size: 1em;"&gt;And the world was calm. The truth in a calm world,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size: 1em;"&gt;In which there is no other meaning, itself&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size: 1em;"&gt;Is calm, itself is summer and night, itself&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size: 1em;"&gt;Is the reader leaning late and reading there.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

</text>
</poem>
<poem>
<author>
Wallace Stevens
</author>
<title>
Anecdote of the Jar
</title>
<text>
I placed a jar in Tennessee,&lt;br&gt;
And round it was, upon a hill.&lt;br&gt;
It made the slovenly wilderness&lt;br&gt;
Surround that hill.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The wilderness rose up to it,&lt;br&gt;
And sprawled around, no longer wild.&lt;br&gt;
The jar was round upon the ground&lt;br&gt;
And tall and of a port in air.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
It took dominion everywhere.&lt;br&gt;
The jar was gray and bare.&lt;br&gt;
It did not give of bird or bush,&lt;br&gt;
Like nothing else in Tennessee.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

</text>
</poem>
<poem>
<author>
Wallace Stevens
</author>
<title>
Bantams in Pine-Woods
</title>
<text>
Chieftain Iffucan of Azcan in caftan&lt;br&gt;
Of tan with henna hackles, halt!&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
Damned universal cock, as if the sun&lt;br&gt;
Was blackamoor to bear your blazing tail.&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
Fat! Fat! Fat! Fat! I am the personal.&lt;br&gt;
Your world is you. I am my world.&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
You ten-foot poet among inchlings. Fat!&lt;br&gt;
Begone! An inchling bristles in these pines,&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
Bristles, and points their Appalachian tangs,&lt;br&gt;
And fears not portly Azcan nor his hoos.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

</text>
</poem>
<poem>
<author>
Wallace Stevens
</author>
<title>
The Snow Man
</title>
<text>
One must have a mind of winter&lt;br&gt;
To regard the frost and the boughs&lt;br&gt;
Of the pine-trees crusted with snow;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
And have been cold a long time&lt;br&gt;
To behold the junipers shagged with ice,&lt;br&gt;
The spruces rough in the distant glitter&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Of the January sun; and not to think&lt;br&gt;
Of any misery in the sound of the wind,&lt;br&gt;
In the sound of a few leaves,&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Which is the sound of the land&lt;br&gt;
Full of the same wind&lt;br&gt;
That is blowing in the same bare place&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
For the listener, who listens in the snow,&lt;br&gt;
And, nothing himself, beholds&lt;br&gt;
Nothing that is not there and the nothing that is.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

</text>
</poem>
<poem>
<author>
Emily Dickinson
</author>
<title>
This World is not Conclusion (373)
</title>
<text>
This World is not Conclusion.&lt;br&gt;
A Species stands beyond - &lt;br&gt;
Invisible, as Music -&lt;br&gt;
But positive, as Sound -&lt;br&gt;
It beckons, and it baffles - &lt;br&gt;
Philosophy, dont know - &lt;br&gt;
And through a Riddle, at the last - &lt;br&gt;
Sagacity, must go -&lt;br&gt;
To guess it, puzzles scholars -&lt;br&gt;
To gain it, Men have borne&lt;br&gt;
Contempt of Generations&lt;br&gt;
And Crucifixion, shown -&lt;br&gt;
Faith slips - and laughs, and rallies - &lt;br&gt;
Blushes, if any see - &lt;br&gt;
Plucks at a twig of Evidence - &lt;br&gt;
And asks a Vane, the way - &lt;br&gt;
Much Gesture, from the Pulpit -&lt;br&gt;
Strong Hallelujahs roll - &lt;br&gt;
Narcotics cannot still the Tooth&lt;br&gt;
That nibbles at the soul -&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

</text>
</poem>
<poem>
<author>
Emily Dickinson
</author>
<title>
Much Madness is divinest Sense - (620)
</title>
<text>
Much Madness is divinest Sense -&lt;br&gt;
To a discerning Eye -&lt;br&gt;
Much Sense - the starkest Madness -&lt;br&gt;
’Tis the Majority&lt;br&gt;
In this, as all, prevail -&lt;br&gt;
Assent - and you are sane -&lt;br&gt;
Demur - you’re straightway dangerous -&lt;br&gt;
And handled with a Chain -&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

</text>
</poem>
<poem>
<author>
Emily Dickinson
</author>
<title>
The Props assist the House (729)
</title>
<text>
The Props assist the House&lt;br&gt;
Until the House is built&lt;br&gt;
And then the Props withdraw&lt;br&gt;
And adequate, erect,&lt;br&gt;
The House support itself&lt;br&gt;
And cease to recollect&lt;br&gt;
The Augur and the Carpenter –&lt;br&gt;
Just such a retrospect&lt;br&gt;
Hath the perfected Life –&lt;br&gt;
A Past of Plank and Nail&lt;br&gt;
And slowness – then the scaffolds drop&lt;br&gt;
Affirming it a Soul –&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

</text>
</poem>
<poem>
<author>
John Ashbery
</author>
<title>
Anticipated Stranger,
</title>
<text>
the bruise will stop by later.&lt;br&gt;
For now, the pain pauses in its round,&lt;br&gt;
notes the time of day, the patient’s temperature,&lt;br&gt;
leaves a memo for the surrogate: What the &lt;em&gt;hell&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
did you think you were doing? I mean . . .&lt;br&gt;
Oh well, less said the better, they all say.&lt;br&gt;
I’ll post this at the desk.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
God will find the pattern and break it.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

</text>
</poem>
<poem>
<author>
John Ashbery
</author>
<title>
This Room
</title>
<text>
The room I entered was a dream of this room.&lt;br&gt;
Surely all those feet on the sofa were mine.&lt;br&gt;
The oval portrait&lt;br&gt;
of a dog was me at an early age.&lt;br&gt;
Something shimmers, something is hushed up.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
We had macaroni for lunch every day&lt;br&gt;
except Sunday, when a small quail was induced&lt;br&gt;
to be served to us. Why do I tell you these things?&lt;br&gt;
You are not even here.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

</text>
</poem>
<poem>
<author>
John Ashbery
</author>
<title>
Last Month
</title>
<text>
No changes of support—only&lt;br&gt;
Patches of gray, here where sunlight fell.&lt;br&gt;
The house seems heavier&lt;br&gt;
Now that they have gone away.   &lt;br&gt;
In fact it emptied in record time.   &lt;br&gt;
When the flat table used to result&lt;br&gt;
A match recedes, slowly, into the night.&lt;br&gt;
The academy of the future is   &lt;br&gt;
Opening its doors and willing&lt;br&gt;
The fruitless sunlight streams into domes,   &lt;br&gt;
The chairs piled high with books and papers.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The sedate one is this month’s skittish one   &lt;br&gt;
Confirming the property that,&lt;br&gt;
A timeless value, has changed hands.&lt;br&gt;
And you could have a new automobile&lt;br&gt;
Ping pong set and garage, but the thief   &lt;br&gt;
Stole everything like a miracle.&lt;br&gt;
In his book there was a picture of treason only   &lt;br&gt;
And in the garden, cries and colors.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

</text>
</poem>
<poem>
<author>
John Ashbery
</author>
<title>
Street Musicians
</title>
<text>
One died, and the soul was wrenched out   &lt;br&gt;
Of the other in life, who, walking the streets   &lt;br&gt;
Wrapped in an identity like a coat, sees on and on   &lt;br&gt;
The same corners, volumetrics, shadows   &lt;br&gt;
Under trees. Farther than anyone was ever   &lt;br&gt;
Called, through increasingly suburban airs   &lt;br&gt;
And ways, with autumn falling over everything:   &lt;br&gt;
The plush leaves the chattels in barrels   &lt;br&gt;
Of an obscure family being evicted&lt;br&gt;
Into the way it was, and is. The other beached   &lt;br&gt;
Glimpses of what the other was up to:&lt;br&gt;
Revelations at last. So they grew to hate and forget each other.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
So I cradle this average violin that knows   &lt;br&gt;
Only forgotten showtunes, but argues&lt;br&gt;
The possibility of free declamation anchored&lt;br&gt;
To a dull refrain, the year turning over on itself   &lt;br&gt;
In November, with the spaces among the days   &lt;br&gt;
More literal, the meat more visible on the bone.   &lt;br&gt;
Our question of a place of origin hangs&lt;br&gt;
Like smoke: how we picnicked in pine forests,&lt;br&gt;
In coves with the water always seeping up, and left   &lt;br&gt;
Our trash, sperm and excrement everywhere, smeared   &lt;br&gt;
On the landscape, to make of us what we could.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

</text>
</poem>
<poem>
<author>
Frank O&#039;Hara
</author>
<title>
The Day Lady Died
</title>
<text>
It is 12:20 in New York a Friday&lt;br&gt;
three days after Bastille day, yes&lt;br&gt;
it is 1959 and I go get a shoeshine&lt;br&gt;
because I will get off the 4:19 in Easthampton   &lt;br&gt;
at 7:15 and then go straight to dinner&lt;br&gt;
and I don’t know the people who will feed me&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
I walk up the muggy street beginning to sun   &lt;br&gt;
and have a hamburger and a malted and buy&lt;br&gt;
an ugly &lt;small&gt;NEW WORLD WRITING&lt;/small&gt; to see what the poets   &lt;br&gt;
in Ghana are doing these days&lt;br&gt;
                                                        I go on to the bank&lt;br&gt;
and Miss Stillwagon (first name Linda I once heard)   &lt;br&gt;
doesn’t even look up my balance for once in her life   &lt;br&gt;
and in the &lt;small&gt;GOLDEN GRIFFIN&lt;/small&gt; I get a little Verlaine   &lt;br&gt;
for Patsy with drawings by Bonnard although I do   &lt;br&gt;
think of Hesiod, trans. Richmond Lattimore or   &lt;br&gt;
Brendan Behan’s new play or &lt;em&gt;Le Balcon&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Les Nègres&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
of Genet, but I don’t, I stick with Verlaine&lt;br&gt;
after practically going to sleep with quandariness&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
and for Mike I just stroll into the &lt;small&gt;PARK LANE&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Liquor Store and ask for a bottle of Strega and   &lt;br&gt;
then I go back where I came from to 6th Avenue   &lt;br&gt;
and the tobacconist in the Ziegfeld Theatre and   &lt;br&gt;
casually ask for a carton of Gauloises and a carton&lt;br&gt;
of Picayunes, and a &lt;small&gt;NEW YORK POST&lt;/small&gt; with her face on it&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
and I am sweating a lot by now and thinking of&lt;br&gt;
leaning on the john door in the &lt;small&gt;5 SPOT&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;
while she whispered a song along the keyboard&lt;br&gt;
to Mal Waldron and everyone and I stopped breathing&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

</text>
</poem>
<poem>
<author>
Frank O&#039;Hara
</author>
<title>
A Step Away from Them
</title>
<text>
It’s my lunch hour, so I go&lt;br&gt;
for a walk among the hum-colored   &lt;br&gt;
cabs. First, down the sidewalk   &lt;br&gt;
where laborers feed their dirty   &lt;br&gt;
glistening torsos sandwiches&lt;br&gt;
and Coca-Cola, with yellow helmets   &lt;br&gt;
on. They protect them from falling   &lt;br&gt;
bricks, I guess. Then onto the   &lt;br&gt;
avenue where skirts are flipping   &lt;br&gt;
above heels and blow up over   &lt;br&gt;
grates. The sun is hot, but the   &lt;br&gt;
cabs stir up the air. I look   &lt;br&gt;
at bargains in wristwatches. There   &lt;br&gt;
are cats playing in sawdust.&lt;br&gt;
                                          On&lt;br&gt;
to Times Square, where the sign&lt;br&gt;
blows smoke over my head, and higher   &lt;br&gt;
the waterfall pours lightly. A   &lt;br&gt;
Negro stands in a doorway with a   &lt;br&gt;
toothpick, languorously agitating.   &lt;br&gt;
A blonde chorus girl clicks: he   &lt;br&gt;
smiles and rubs his chin. Everything   &lt;br&gt;
suddenly honks: it is 12:40 of   &lt;br&gt;
a Thursday.&lt;br&gt;
                Neon in daylight is a   &lt;br&gt;
great pleasure, as Edwin Denby would   &lt;br&gt;
write, as are light bulbs in daylight.   &lt;br&gt;
I stop for a cheeseburger at &lt;small&gt;JULIET’S   &lt;br&gt;
CORNER&lt;/small&gt;. Giulietta Masina, wife of   &lt;br&gt;
Federico Fellini, &lt;em&gt;è bell’ attrice. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
And chocolate malted. A lady in   &lt;br&gt;
foxes on such a day puts her poodle   &lt;br&gt;
in a cab.&lt;br&gt;
             There are several Puerto   &lt;br&gt;
Ricans on the avenue today, which   &lt;br&gt;
makes it beautiful and warm. First   &lt;br&gt;
Bunny died, then John Latouche,   &lt;br&gt;
then Jackson Pollock. But is the   &lt;br&gt;
earth as full as life was full, of them?   &lt;br&gt;
And one has eaten and one walks,   &lt;br&gt;
past the magazines with nudes   &lt;br&gt;
and the posters for &lt;small&gt;BULLFIGHT&lt;/small&gt; and   &lt;br&gt;
the Manhattan Storage Warehouse,   &lt;br&gt;
which they’ll soon tear down. I   &lt;br&gt;
used to think they had the Armory   &lt;br&gt;
Show there.&lt;br&gt;
                A glass of papaya juice   &lt;br&gt;
and back to work. My heart is in my   &lt;br&gt;
pocket, it is Poems by Pierre Reverdy.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

</text>
</poem>
<poem>
<author>
Emily Dickinson
</author>
<title>
There is no Frigate like a Book (1286)
</title>
<text>
There is no Frigate like a Book&lt;br&gt;
To take us Lands away&lt;br&gt;
Nor any Coursers like a Page&lt;br&gt;
Of prancing Poetry –&lt;br&gt;
This Traverse may the poorest take&lt;br&gt;
Without oppress of Toll –&lt;br&gt;
How frugal is the Chariot&lt;br&gt;
That bears the Human Soul –&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

</text>
</poem>
<poem>
<author>
Kenneth Koch
</author>
<title>
On the Great Atlantic Rainway
</title>
<text>
I set forth one misted white day of June&lt;br&gt;
Beneath the great Atlantic rainway, and heard:&lt;br&gt;
“Honestly you smite worlds of truth, but&lt;br&gt;
Lose your own trains of thought, like a pigeon.&lt;br&gt;
Did you once ride in Kenneth’s machine?”&lt;br&gt;
“Yes, I rode there, an old man in shorts, blind,&lt;br&gt;
Who had lost his way in the filling station; Kenneth was kind.”&lt;br&gt;
“Did he fill your motionless ears with resonance and stain?”&lt;br&gt;
“No, he spoke not as a critic, but as a man.”&lt;br&gt;
“Tell me, what did he say?” “He said,&lt;br&gt;
‘My eyes are the white sky, the gravel on the groundway my sad lament.’”&lt;br&gt;
“And yet he drives between the two. . . .” “Exactly, Jane,&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
And that is the modern idea of fittingness,&lt;br&gt;
To, always in motion, lose nothing, although beneath the&lt;br&gt;
Rainway they move in threes and twos completely&lt;br&gt;
Ruined for themselves, like moving pictures.”&lt;br&gt;
“But how other?” “Formulalessness, to go from the sun&lt;br&gt;
Into love’s sweet disrepair. He would fondly express&lt;br&gt;
‘Rain trees’—which is not a poem, ‘rain trees. . . .’”&lt;br&gt;
“Still, it is mysterious to have an engine&lt;br&gt;
That floats bouquets! and one day in the rear-vision&lt;br&gt;
Mirror of his car we vowed delight,&lt;br&gt;
The insufficiency of the silverware in the sunlight,&lt;br&gt;
The dreams he steals from and smiles, losing gain.”&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
“Yet always beneath the rainway unsyntactical&lt;br&gt;
Beauty might leap up!” “That we might sing&lt;br&gt;
From smiles’ ravines, ‘Rose, the reverse of everything,&lt;br&gt;
May be profaned or talked at like a hat.’”&lt;br&gt;
“Oh that was sweet and short, like the minuet&lt;br&gt;
Of stars, which would permit us to seem our best friends&lt;br&gt;
By silver’s eminent lights! For nature is so small, ends&lt;br&gt;
Falsely reign, distending the time we did&lt;br&gt;
Behind our hope for body-work, riding with Kenneth.”&lt;br&gt;
Their voicing ceased, then started again, to complain&lt;br&gt;
That we are offered nothing when it starts to rain&lt;br&gt;
In the same way, though we are dying for the truth.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

</text>
</poem>
<poem>
<author>
Kenneth Koch
</author>
<title>
To You
</title>
<text>
I love you as a sheriff searches for a walnut&lt;br&gt;
That will solve a murder case unsolved for years&lt;br&gt;
Because the murderer left it in the snow beside a window&lt;br&gt;
Through which he saw her head, connecting with&lt;br&gt;
Her shoulders by a neck, and laid a red&lt;br&gt;
Roof in her heart. For this we live a thousand years;&lt;br&gt;
For this we love, and we live because we love, we are not&lt;br&gt;
Inside a bottle, thank goodness! I love you as a&lt;br&gt;
Kid searches for a goat; I am crazier than shirttails&lt;br&gt;
In the wind, when you’re near, a wind that blows from&lt;br&gt;
The big blue sea, so shiny so deep and so unlike us;&lt;br&gt;
I think I am bicycling across an Africa of green and white fields&lt;br&gt;
Always, to be near you, even in my heart&lt;br&gt;
When I’m awake, which swims, and also I believe that you&lt;br&gt;
Are trustworthy as the sidewalk which leads me to&lt;br&gt;
The place where I again think of you, a new&lt;br&gt;
Harmony of thoughts! I love you as the sunlight leads the prow&lt;br&gt;
Of a ship which sails&lt;br&gt;
From Hartford to Miami, and I love you&lt;br&gt;
Best at dawn, when even before I am awake the sun&lt;br&gt;
Receives me in the questions which you always pose.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

</text>
</poem>
<poem>
<author>
Kenneth Koch
</author>
<title>
Variations on a Theme by William Carlos Williams
</title>
<text>
&lt;span&gt;                                                                  1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
I chopped down the house that you had been saving to live in next&lt;br&gt;
     summer.&lt;br&gt;
I am sorry, but it was morning, and I had nothing to do&lt;br&gt;
and its wooden beams were so inviting.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
                                                                  2&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
We laughed at the hollyhocks together&lt;br&gt;
and then I sprayed them with lye.&lt;br&gt;
Forgive me. I simply do not know what I am doing.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
                                                                  3&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
I gave away the money that you had been saving to live on for the next ten&lt;br&gt;
     years.&lt;br&gt;
The man who asked for it was shabby&lt;br&gt;
and the firm March wind on the porch was so juicy and cold.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
                                                                  4&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Last evening we went dancing and I broke your leg.&lt;br&gt;
Forgive me. I was clumsy, and&lt;br&gt;
I wanted you here in the wards, where I am the doctor!&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;

</text>
</poem>
<poem>
<author>
William Carlos Williams
</author>
<title>
Dedication for a Plot of Ground
</title>
<text>
This plot of ground&lt;br&gt;
facing the waters of this inlet&lt;br&gt;
is dedicated to the living presence of&lt;br&gt;
Emily Dickinson Wellcome&lt;br&gt;
who was born in England; married;&lt;br&gt;
lost her husband and with&lt;br&gt;
her five year old son&lt;br&gt;
sailed for New York in a two-master;&lt;br&gt;
was driven to the Azores;&lt;br&gt;
ran adrift on Fire Island shoal,&lt;br&gt;
met her second husband&lt;br&gt;
in a Brooklyn boarding house,&lt;br&gt;
went with him to Puerto Rico&lt;br&gt;
bore three more children, lost&lt;br&gt;
her second husband, lived hard&lt;br&gt;
for eight years in St. Thomas,&lt;br&gt;
Puerto Rico, San Domingo, followed&lt;br&gt;
the oldest son to New York,&lt;br&gt;
lost her daughter, lost her "baby,"&lt;br&gt;
seized the two boys of&lt;br&gt;
the oldest son by the second marriage&lt;br&gt;
mothered them—they being&lt;br&gt;
motherless—fought for them&lt;br&gt;
against the other grandmother&lt;br&gt;
and the aunts, brought them here&lt;br&gt;
summer after summer, defended&lt;br&gt;
herself here against thieves,&lt;br&gt;
storms, sun, fire,&lt;br&gt;
against flies, against girls&lt;br&gt;
that came smelling about, against&lt;br&gt;
drought, against weeds, storm-tides,&lt;br&gt;
neighbors, weasels that stole her chickens,&lt;br&gt;
against the weakness of her own hands,&lt;br&gt;
against the growing strength of&lt;br&gt;
the boys, against wind, against&lt;br&gt;
the stones, against trespassers,&lt;br&gt;
against rents, against her own mind.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
She grubbed this earth with her own hands,&lt;br&gt;
domineered over this grass plot,&lt;br&gt;
blackguarded her oldest son&lt;br&gt;
into buying it, lived here fifteen years,&lt;br&gt;
attained a final loneliness and—&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
If you can bring nothing to this place&lt;br&gt;
but your carcass, keep out.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

</text>
</poem>
<poem>
<author>
William Carlos Williams
</author>
<title>
Danse Russe
</title>
<text>
If I when my wife is sleeping&lt;br&gt;
and the baby and Kathleen&lt;br&gt;
are sleeping&lt;br&gt;
and the sun is a flame-white disc&lt;br&gt;
in silken mists&lt;br&gt;
above shining trees,—&lt;br&gt;
if I in my north room&lt;br&gt;
dance naked, grotesquely&lt;br&gt;
before my mirror&lt;br&gt;
waving my shirt round my head&lt;br&gt;
and singing softly to myself:&lt;br&gt;
“I am lonely, lonely.&lt;br&gt;
I was born to be lonely,&lt;br&gt;
I am best so!”&lt;br&gt;
If I admire my arms, my face,&lt;br&gt;
my shoulders, flanks, buttocks&lt;br&gt;
against the yellow drawn shades,—&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Who shall say I am not&lt;br&gt;
the happy genius of my household?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

</text>
</poem>
<poem>
<author>
William Carlos Williams
</author>
<title>
Love Song
</title>
<text>
I lie here thinking of you:—&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
the stain of love &lt;br&gt;
is upon the world!&lt;br&gt;
Yellow, yellow, yellow&lt;br&gt;
it eats into the leaves,&lt;br&gt;
smears with saffron&lt;br&gt;
the horned branches that lean&lt;br&gt;
heavily&lt;br&gt;
against a smooth purple sky!&lt;br&gt;
There is no light&lt;br&gt;
only a honey-thick stain&lt;br&gt;
that drips from leaf to leaf&lt;br&gt;
and limb to limb&lt;br&gt;
spoiling the colors&lt;br&gt;
of the whole world—&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
you far off there under&lt;br&gt;
the wine-red selvage of the west! &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

</text>
</poem>
<poem>
<author>
William Carlos Williams
</author>
<title>
This Is Just To Say
</title>
<text>
I have eaten&lt;br&gt;
the plums&lt;br&gt;
that were in&lt;br&gt;
the icebox&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
and which&lt;br&gt;
you were probably&lt;br&gt;
saving&lt;br&gt;
for breakfast&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Forgive me&lt;br&gt;
they were delicious&lt;br&gt;
so sweet&lt;br&gt;
and so cold&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

</text>
</poem>
</xml>
